Amanda Monteiro

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

ABOUT

I strive to create a meaningful user experience that is accessible across all screen sizes or through assistive technology. I take initiative and find creative solutions to problems before they even have a chance to arise. I'm a lifelong mediator when conflicts occur after growing up as a middle child and I will step up as a leader when needed.

SKILLS

- HTML5
- CSS3, SCSS
- JavaScript (ES6)
- iQuery
- REST APIs
- React
- Firebase
- Git/GitHub
- Responsive Design
- Web Accessibility
- PSD Conversion
- Pair/Mob Programming
- Leadership

EDUCATION

Juno College of Technology Web Development Certificate

- Immersive Web Development, Oct Dec 2020
- Accelerated JavaScript, Sep Oct 2020
- Web Development 101, Jul 2020

University of WaterlooBachelor of Science in Psychology, Biology Minor

- September 2010 April 2014
- Residence Life Advisor, Sep 2013 Apr 2014
- Orientation Week Leader, Sep 2012
- Science First Year Rep, Sep 2010 Apr 2011

CONTACT

Email: a3monteiro@gmail.com

Portfolio: amandamonteiro.ca

LinkedIn: amandamonteiro-3

GitHub: armontei

Twitter: amandamcodes

FEATURED PROJECTS

I Dream of Cleannie | React, Firebase, Sass

A react based app that allows users to enter cleaning tasks for different rooms in their homes. Users can mark each task as complete or delete the task. Users can also click a button to generate a random suggested task based on the room. Data is saved in Firebase.

A Moment of Calm | jQuery, Sass

An app that utilizes jQuery to allow users to select a background image, an audio file to play, and set a timer. Alternatively, users can select a random image, audio, or timer value. An animation will start if the user chooses to have a visualizer accompany the timer.

Meme in a Giffy | React, Firebase, Rest API, Sass

Agency style group project where users can create memes by searching for gifs with the Giphy API and adding text to it. Memes are saved through Firebase and users can search through memes already created by using keywords. Users can upvote or downvote memes.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Health Surveillance Screener

University Health Network | Jul 2020 - Oct 2020

- Used knowledge of hospital guidelines to direct patient flow in the hospital resulting in mitigating the spread of Covid-19
- Responded to queries and concerns in a professional, respectful, and courteous manner, resulting in a more positive visitor experience
- Collaborated with the shift coordinator to maximize the efficiency in screening areas resulting in shorter wait times

Office Administrator

Orthogenic Laboratories Inc. | Nov 2015 - Mar 2020

- Effectively handled accounts payable using QuickBooks Pro and Xero, ensuring bills were paid on time
- Successfully assisted clients through phone calls, email correspondence, and FreshDesk which improved overall customer satisfaction
- Meticulously created and updated records and databases with sensitive client, financial and other data ensuring records were always accurate and up to date